

Daniel Banciu

M.Sc. Computer Scence

- **6** +49 1573 31 91 308
- @ daniel02_banciu@yahoo.de

Skills

Backend Development

Java, Python, Springboot/ VertX, **REST**

Frontend Development

ReactJS, HTML/CSS

Machine Learning

Classification, Regression, Vision-Transformers, deeplearning-weatherprediction models, CNN

Data Science

explainable AI, Correlation, Patterns

Awards

Deutschlandstipendium (scholarship) 2019-2020

Languages

German Native

English

Fluent

Romanian

Native



Italian

A2/B1 Recent Master's graduate from the University of Tübingen with a focus on data science. I run a side business as an external data protection consultant. I have been working as a software developer since 2019, both full-time and part-time. I bring strong communication skills and ambition to my work.

For more details on my CV and projects, please visit my website.

Profiles

O dbanciu

in daniel-banciu

Education

University of Tübingen

Computer Science

https://uni-tuebingen.de/en/

Tübingen, Germany

Heilbronn University of Applied Sciences

Software Engineering

https://www.hs-heilbronn.de/en

Heilbronn, Germany

Immanuel-Kant-Gymnasium

Leinfelden-Echterdingen, Germany

September 2017 - August 2021

October 2021 - April 2024

Master of Science

Bachelor of Science

2009-2017 High School

Experience

Vector Informatik GmbH

Software Developer

https://www.vector.com/de/de/

Stuttgart, Germany

November 2020 - March 2023

Bachelor Thesis, Full-Time between Bachelor's and Master's, working student.

eXXcellent solutions consulting & software GmbH

Software Developer

https://www.exxcellent.de/

Internship and working student.

August 2019 - November 2020 Stuttgart, Germany

Own small Side Business

External data protection consultant

External data protection consultant and IT consultant specialised for dentists.

2023-2024

Theses

Exploring Latent

Representations for Tübingen, Germany

Identifying Forecasting Opportunities in Deep

Learning Weather Models

Master Thesis

Investigated the predictive capabilities of FourCastNet, a deep learning weather prediction model, focusing on its utilisation of the Madden-Julian Oscillation (MJO) for enhancing weather forecast accuracy. Analysed predictive performance metrics such as root-mean-square-error and anomaly correlation coefficient.

Data Science, Machine Learning, Python

Predictive Analysis of

Electric Vehicles during Heilbronn, Germany

2021

April 2018 - Present

Charging to Optimize Load Management

Algorithms

Bachelor Thesis at

Vector GmbH

Developed a critical feature for the vCharM system by Vector Informatik GmbH to enhance load management in electric vehicle charging networks. This feature involved gathering and analyzing vehicle charging data to refine load management algorithms, thereby optimizing power grid operations in residential and company settings.

Java, FullStack

Volunteering	Projects
Digitale Sprechstunde 2020 Stuttgart, Germany	Fair Machin Seminar Course at T
Helping old people with all IT-related things such as setting up their smartphone and explaining how to write e-mails etc	Evaluation of attribution tabular data
Jugendgemeinderat (local politics youth council) founding member 2016	LIME attrib Using a trail language n GReaT.
Leinfelden-Echterdingen, Germany	Machine Lea
Interests Karate Jiu Jitsu	
Karate Jiu Jitsu E-Sports Gym	Self Driving Machine Le Challenges Self Driving course at T Challenges imitation le reinforcem the car gyn Machine Lea Imitation Lea Reinforceme

rair Machine Learning 2023 Pose eminar Mach

Course at Tübingen

Evaluation the effectiveness of attribution methods for tabular data. Comparing the performance of SHAP and LIME attribution methods. Using a transformer-based language model, known as

Machine Learning, explainable AI

Self Driving Cars Machine Learning Challenges Self Driving Cars course at Tübingen

Challenges involved imitation learning and reinforcement learning using the car gym environment.

Machine Learning, PyTorch, mitation Learning, Reinforcement Learning

Pose Estimation Machine Learning

Course Project of "ML and Vision" at Tübingen

As part of the course
"Praktikum Bildverarbeitung,
Maschinelles Lernen und
Computer Vision" we show
how we developed a pytorch
implementation of the paper
'Toward fast and accurate
human pose estimation via
soft-gated skip
connections'.

Machine Learning, CNN, PyTorch

BUGA 2019 App 2019 Bachelor's "big project" at Heilbronn

Development of an application for the Bundesgartenschau 2019 in Heilbronn as part of the big project in the 5th semester of the bachelor's degree.

Fullstack, Java, React, Scrum

NLP Analysis

2022

Course Project of "Data Literacy" at Tübingen

2022

Analysis of an unknown data set in a project in teams of two. We analysed every speech in the Bundestag and tried to answer questions like "How has the language developed?"

Data Science, NLP